Guide to the Hans Reichenbach Papers, 1884-1972 ASP.1973.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Hans Reichenbach Papers
1884-1979
1909-1953
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Reichenbach, Hans
ASP.1973.01
40.26 Linear Feet
Hans Reichenbach (September 26, 1891–April 9, 1953) was an influential philosopher of science, educator, and proponent of logical empiricism. He founded the Gesellschaft für empirische Philosophie (Society for Empirical Philosophy) in Berlin in 1928, also known as the "Berlin Circle." Throughout his career Reichenbach made lasting contributions to the analysis of probabilistic reasoning; logic and the philosophy of mathematics; quantum mechanics; and space, time, and relativity theory. The Hans Reichenbach Papers comprise published and unpublished manuscripts, lectures, correspondence, photographs, drawings, and related materials from his early student days until his death.
Acquisition Information
The Hans Reichenbach Papers were acquired from Reichenbach's widow, Maria Reichenbach, in 1973.
Biography
Hans Reichenbach (September 26, 1891–April 9, 1953) was an influential philosopher of science, educator, and proponent of logical empiricism. He founded the Gesellschaft für empirische Philosophie (Society for Empirical Philosophy) in Berlin in 1928, also known as the "Berlin Circle." Carl Gustav Hempel, Richard von Mises, David Hilbert and Kurt Grelling all became members of the Berlin Circle. Reichenbach took on another major role in 1930 when, together with Carnap, he became the editor of the journal Erkenntnis (Knowledge). Throughout his career Hans Reichenbach made lasting contributions to the analysis of probabilistic reasoning; logic and the philosophy of mathematics; quantum mechanics; and space, time, and relativity theory. He was also concerned with elaborating a cogent and consistent empiricism based on a theory of probability.
Scope and Content Notes
The Hans Reichenbach Papers comprise published and unpublished manuscripts, lectures, correspondence, photographs, drawings, and related materials from his early student days until his death.
The correspondence contains about 9,000 pages to and from Reichenbach; it ranges over his entire career. Those with whom Reichenbach maintained lifelong contact include Rudolf Carnap, Ernst Cassirer, Herbert Feigl, Philip Frank, Carl Hempel, Sidney Hook, Paul Oppenheim and Wolfgang Pauli. In addition, there is significant correspondence with von Astor, Bergmann, Bertalanffy, Dingler, Dubislav, Einstein, Fraenkel, Frank, Freundlich, Grelling, Grünbaum, Paul Hertz, Hutten, Jordan, Landé, von Laue, Lewin, C.I. Lewis, Charles Morris, Nagel, Neurath, Northrop, Planck, Quine, Regener, Rougier, Salmon, Schillp, Schlick, Scholz, Schrödinger, Martin Strauss, Tarski, Vaihinger, Weiss, Williams, Zawarski, and Zilsel. The correspondence provides a valuable source of information about Reichenbach's personal and philosophical development. It also provides primary source material for research into one of the 20th century most influential philosophical movements.
Reichenbach's manuscripts include many of his own notes as a student. Some go as far back as his university days in science and mathematics. Some of the most significant of these notes are those taken by him as a student of Albert Einstein on the special and general theories of relativity. There are four such notebooks dating from 1918. In addition there are his student notes on astronomy, Planck and electricity, Hilbert's "Statistical Mechanics" and "Problems and Principles."
He also kept many of his lecture notes from Germany, Turkey, and the United States. The number of lectures runs to over 100 and provides a glimpse into the problems of philosophy and how he presented them to his students. Many of his lectures discussed principles of radio and issues in philosophy and modern science, often in form of popularizations of questions in relativity and quantum theory delivered on radio programs for a wider audiences. In addition to this there are an abundance of notes, calculations, and diagrams used to draft both published and unpublished papers.
Arrangement
During the initial processing of the Reichenbach Papers, an effort was made to preserve the order in which they were received, although since his death, Maria Reichenbach had still been working with them in order to keep publishing many unpublished manuscripts. As a result, there might have been some disturbance to Reichenbach's original order. Researchers should note that specific types of formats, such as manuscripts or correspondence, can be found throughout the series of the papers.
Arrangement:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Early Correspondence, Photos, and Probability Notes
Series III: Correspondence, Drawings, Manuscripts, Notebooks, and Photographs
Series IV: Name Index
Previous Citation
Hans Reichenbach Papers, 1884-1972, ASP.1973.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Existence and Location of Copies
A microfilm copy of the papers is available at the Philosophical Archive of Konstanz Univeristy in Konstanz, Germany: http://www.uni-konstanz.de/FuF/Philo/philarchiv/bestaende/Reichenbach.htm.
Physics -- Philosophy; Science -- Philosophy -- History -- 20th century; Science -- Philosophy -- History -- Sources; Science -- Philosophy; Knowledge, Theory of; Space and time; Reichenbach, Hans; Zilsel, Edgar; Russell, Bertrand; Neurath, Otto; Nagel, Ernest; Lewis, Clarence Irving; Lewin, Kurt; Cassirer, Ernst; Dubislav, Walter; Einstein, Albert; Feigl, Herbert; Frank, Philipp; Grelling, Kurt; Hertz, Paul; Hempel, Carl G. (Carl Gustav); Hook, Sidney; Laue, Max von
- Correspondence, 1919-1938; 1930-1938; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I comprises Hans Reichenbach's correspondence. Each subseries covers a specific range of years. Within this range, the letters are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the authors, according to Hans Reichenbach's original organization. If a folder contains only correspondence relating to one individual, the complete name is listed.
  - Correspondence Berlin and Istanbul, 1930-1938; 1.
    - Ajdukiewicz, Kazimierz, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - A, 1930 - 1933 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - B, 1931 - 1936 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - B, 1935-1937 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - C, 1930 - 1937 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - C, 1930-1936 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - D, 1930-1934 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Driesch, Hans, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Dubislav, Walter, 1933-1934 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Feigl, Herbert, 1931-1937 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - F, 1934-1936 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Gödel, Kurt, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Grelling, Kurt, 1935-1937 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - H, 1930-1937 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - H, 1930-1932 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - J, 1932-1935 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Köhler, Wolfgang, 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Krishnama & Rajagopa, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Laurwerys, J., 1937 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - L, 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Löwy, Heinrich, 1932-1933 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Malisoff, W.M., 1935-1936 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Felix Meiner Verlag, 1930-1938 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - N, 1930-1938 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - P- S, 1933-1935 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - P, 1930-1933 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Requard, Fritz, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Russell, Bertrand, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - S, 1930-1936 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Scholz, Heinrich, 1930-1935 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Sch, 1930-1938 (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Spemann, Hans, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Steinhardt, Käthe, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - St, 1930-1937 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - T, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - W, 1931-1936 (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Z, 1930-1938 (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - A, 1933-1936 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - B, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - C, 1930-1938 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - D, 1934-1938 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - E, 1933-1936 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - F, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - G, 1933-1937 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - H, 1932-1938 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - J, 1933 - 1935 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - K, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - L, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - M, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - N, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - O, 1934-1936 (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - P, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - R, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - S, 1931-1938 (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - Sch - St, 1933-1937 (Box 13, Folder 56)
    - T, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - U, 1933 - 1934 (Box 13, Folder 58)
    - V - W, 1933-1938 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - Yurtsan, Ferit, 1937 (Box 13, Folder 60)
    - Z, 1933-1937 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, November 1928 to October 1929; 2.
    - A, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - B, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - C, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - D, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - F, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - G, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - H, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - K, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - L, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - M, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - N- O, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - P, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - R, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - S, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - S, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - S, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - T - V, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - V, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - W, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - A, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - B, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - C, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - D, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - E, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - F, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - G, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - H, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - J, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - K, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - L, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - M, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - N - O, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - P, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - R, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - S, 1929-1930 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Sch, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - St, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - T - U, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Verein zur Förderung des physikalischen Unterrichts (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - W, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Z, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - A, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - B, 1931-1932 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - C, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Deutsche Buchgemeinschaft, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - D, 1929-1933 (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - E, 1931-1932 (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Flammarion, siehe Gaulltier (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - G, 1930-1933 (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - H, 1930-1933 (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - J, 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - K, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - L, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 54)
    - M, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 55)
    - Naturwissenschaften, 1931-1935 (Box 14, Folder 56)
    - Northrop, F.S.C., 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 57)
    - P, 1931-1934 (Box 14, Folder 58)
    - R, 1930-1933 (Box 14, Folder 59)
    - Suhrkamp: siehe Neue Rundschau (Box 14, Folder 60)
    - Sch, 1931 (Box 14, Item 61)
    - St, 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 62)
    - T, 1930-1932 (Box 14, Folder 63)
    - V (Box 14, Folder 64)
    - W, 1930-1932 (Box 14, Folder 65)
    - Z, 1932-1933 (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, August 1926 to September 1927; 3.
    - Aster, Friedrich, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - B, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - C, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - D, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Elektrotechnische Zeitschrift, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - F, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - G, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - H, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - J, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - K, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - L, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - M, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - N, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Oppenheim, Paul, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - P, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - R, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - S, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Sch, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - St, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - T, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Umschau, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - V, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - W, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Z, 1926-1927 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, October 1927 to November 1928; 4.
    - A, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - B, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - C, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - D, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - E, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - F, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - G, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - H, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - I - J, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - K, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - L, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - M, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - N - O, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - P, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - R, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Springer, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Sch, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - St, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - T - U, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Vossische Zeitung, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - W, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Z, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, January 1919 to June 1923; 5.
    - List of Correspondents (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Adler, Friedrich, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - B, 1919-1923 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - C, 1921-1923 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - D, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - E, 1921-1923 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - F, 1921-1923 (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - G, 1921-1922 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - H, 1920-1923 (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - K, 1917-1923 (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - L, 1919-1922 (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - M, 1920-1923 (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - O, 1921-1922 (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - P, 1920-1923 (Box 15, Folder 60)
    - R, 1920-1921 (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - Smekal, Adolf, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - Sch, 1919-1923 (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - St, 1919-1921 (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - Thost, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - Utzinger, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - Vaihinger, H., 1922 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Wyrih, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, February 1925 to July 1926; 6.
    - A, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Berliner, Arnold, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - C, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Dubislav, Walter, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - E, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - F, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - G, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - H, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Juttner, F., 1926 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - K, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - L, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - M, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Notgemeinschaft, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Oppenheim, Paul, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - P, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Raviez, Edouard, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - S, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Sch, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - St, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - T, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - U, 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Vieweg, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - W, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Z, 1924-1926 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, July 1923 to February 1925; 7.
    - "Bericht über die Berliner Besprechung vom 19.10.23 zur Gründung der Zeitschrift für philosophische Forschung" and Russell Typescript "Vagueness", 1923 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - A, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - B, 1923-1925 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - C, 1923-1924 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - D, 1923-1925 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Erda, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - F, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - G, 1924-1925 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - H, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Jaspers, K., 1923 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - K, 1923-1924 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - L, 1923-1924 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - M, 1924-1925 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - N - O, 1923-1925 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - P, 1923-1924 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - R, 1923-1925 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - S, 1923-1925 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Sch, 1923-1925 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Steinkopff, Theodor, 1925 (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - T - U, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Vieweg, 1923-1924 (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - W, 1923-1924 (Box 16, Folder 46)
- Early Family Correspondence, Photos, and Probability Notes, 1915-1967; II.
  As evident from the title, Series II comprises an array of materials ranging from family correspondence to manuscript drafts, early notes, and photographs. This organisation reflects the original arrangement.
  - Early Notes (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - "The Meaning and Use of Probability Methods in the Social Sciences" (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - "Der Begriff der Wahrscheinlichkeit für die mathematische Darstellung der Wirklichkeit" (1.-3. Kapitel), 1916 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Probability Notes (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Physics Notes (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Family Correspondence, 1915-1927 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Photos - His Girlfriend (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Probability Feedback (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Probability Notes (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - "Mathematical Theory of Zero-Sum Two-Person Games with a Finite Number or a Continuum of Strategies", 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Papers on the Probability of War", 1949 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - "Report on the Probability of War Study", 1950 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy of Physics (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Logic Seminar - R. Carnap, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Semantics - R. Carnap, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Epistemology - R. Carnap, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Foundations of Mathematics - R. Carnap (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Qualifying Exams, Logic, Scientific Philosophy, Social Philosophy, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - National Science Foundation Fellowship, 1961-1965 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - International Congress of Philosophy of Science, Sao Paulo, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - "Rationalism and Empiricism", 1948 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, Drawings, Manuscripts, Notebooks, and Photographs, 1884-1952; III.
  As with Series II, Series III covers of a wide range of topics and time periods, which reflects the original arrangement of the documents.
  - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Photographs, 1932-1952; 1.
    - Photographs: Reichenbach, Elisabeth (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Charcoal Drawings (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Photographs (of H.R.?), Materials on Arial Photography, 1943-1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Early Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Manuscripts, Newspaper Article, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Manuscripts, 1914 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Lingener, Elisabeth (geb. Meyer), "C.F. Meyers Dichtung Huttens letzte Tage soll nach Inhalt und Form analysiert werden mit Hinblick auf die verschiedenen Fassungen." (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Manuscript by H.R., "Statistisches Verfahren zur Beurteilung von Verstärkerröhren" (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Manuscript by H.R., "Kants Behandlung des Kausalprinzips" (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Map of the Marmara Sea (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Manuscripts by H.R.: "L'empricisme logique et la desagregation de l'apriori" (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Manual and Diagrams for a Record Player (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Manuscripts, 1932-1933 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Manuscripts, 1919 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Graphs (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Pamphlet from Freie Studentenschaft Stuttgart, 1910 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Manuscript-Buch for Erkenntnis (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Chest X-Ray of H.R. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Photographs: H.R., Family, Landscapes (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Drawings labeled "Alte Arbeiten (bis 1910)" (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Lingener, Elisabeth, "Der Bergriff der Willensfreiheit bei Windelband" (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Bargman, Valentin: Correspondence, 1940-1951 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - American Academy of Arts and Science, Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Pauli, W: Correspondence, 1942-1948 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Philosophy Congress in Argentina, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Neurath, Otto: Correspondence, 1938-1946 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Wiler, H: Correspondence, 1941-1951 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Ultgevers, A.W. Sijthoff: Correspondence, 1941-1949 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Essays on Classical Mechanics (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Institute for the Unity of Science: Minutes, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - International Union for Philosophy of Science, Correspondence, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Freund, John: Correspondence, 1948-1951 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Morris, Charles: Correspondence, 1939-1947 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Frank, Philipp: Correspondence, 1947-1952 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Frank, Philipp and Ernest Nagel: Correspondence, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Arzt-Sachen, 1938-1951 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Wohnung, 1938-1941 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Photographs, 1884-1952; 2.
    - Photographs, 1911 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Psychologische Untersuchungen an Volkshochschulkindern, 1912-1913 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Manuscripts - Probability (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Radio-Vortragskorrespondenz, 1927-1933 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Drawings for Space and Time and The Direction of Time, Berlin, 1927-1933 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Manuscripts: Philosophy, Speculation or Science? Philosophical Foundations of Probability Additions to Truth and Error (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence Miscellaneous, 1936-1937 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Alte Entwürfe zur Wahrscheinlichkeit (Berlin) [Old Notes on Probability (Berlin)] (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Manuscripts on Space and Time (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Manuscripts on Space and Time (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Materials Mostly Concerning H.R.'s move from Istanbul to the U.S., 1937 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Photos and Correspondence, 1910 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Article "Etwas vom Impfen", 1909 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Selected Essays (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence from 1884 to 1925; Miscellaneous, 1884-1925 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence; Various letters [Hans Galama- H.R.'s brother], 1952 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Selected Essays (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Notebooks, 1903-1951; 3.
    - Notebooks: Zeichnungen and Kinetische Theorie, 1909 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks: Kinetische Theorie II and III (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks: Mathematik & Aufsätze, 1907-1908 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Notebooks: Diktate & Konstruktionen, 1903-1905 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Notebooks: Rechnen & Kladde, 1903 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks: Wichtige Arbeiten & Aufsätze, 1903 and 1909 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Notebook: Experimente (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Notebook: Biologie and Others (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Notebooks: Religion & Heiteres zum Vortragen, 1909 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Photos (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Family Correspondence, 1911 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Family Correspondence, 1914-1915 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Family Correspondence, 1911 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Time Book - Copy 1, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - "Philosophy and Physics" (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Faculty Research Lecture - "Philosophy and Physics" (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - "Bemerkungen zur Hypothesenwahrscheinlichkeit" (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Space-Time Manuscript (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Probability Logic, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Cube of Logic (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Philosophic Foundation of Q.M. (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Atom und Kosmos (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Die Sozialisierung der Hochschule (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Meaning & Use of Probability Methods in Social Sciences (Box 23, Folder 24)